# ALEKSEI BELONOVSKII

#### PhD, Senior Software Engineer

abelonovskii.github.io

in aleksei-belonovskii

@ aleksei.belonovskii@gmail.com

Montenegro

### **SKILLS**

**Phononics** 

Spectroscopy

**Quantum Optics** 

**Academic Writing** 

Numerical Simulation

Laboratory experience

Light-matter interactions

Condensed matter physics

MATLAB

Mathematica

**COMSOL** 

C# | Python |

C++

MySQL

PostgreSQL

MS SQL

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Russian

## **PUBLICATIONS**

My website

ResearchGate profile

Web of Science profile

### **ABOUT ME**

Research Scientist in condensed matter physics with a PhD awarded in 2021. I am an author and co-author of about 30 peer-reviewed scientific publications. Concurrently, I have 7 years of experience in software development and engineering. I am delighted to apply my knowledge in physics and software engineering to work on innovative projects. My experience in both fields allows me to approach problems from multiple perspectives.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Software Engineer | Tungsten Automation (Kofax)

**1**0 2021 - Current

Working in the Emergency Response Escalation Team for various R&D departments.

#### Researcher | ITMO University & Alferov university

**1** 06 2019 - 06 2022 & 09 2020 - 05 2022

Pursued scientific research in photonics and quantum optics, actively participated in grant-funded projects, published scientific papers, and was an active participant at international photonics conferences.

#### Researcher | C# / WPF Desktop Software Developer | RIVS

**i** 05 2017 - 10 2021

Conducted research in X-ray fluorescence analysis. Developed C# software for automating X-ray analysis and factory equipment management.

#### Engineer | loffe Institute

**i** 10 2016 - 05 2017

Studied black hole physics.

## **EDUCATION**

PhD, Condensed Matter and Materials Physics ITMO University & Alferov university

**2017 - 2021** 

Saint Petersburg , Russia

Master's degree, Theoretical and Mathematical Physics Alferov university

**2015 - 2017** 

Saint Petersburg , Russia

Bachelor's degree, Astrophysics Peter the Great St.Petersburg Polytechnic University

**2011 - 2015** 

Saint Petersburg , Russia